# **Curriculum Vitae**

## **Contact Information**

Name | Manuel Luís Henriques de Araújo

Address | Avenida Rovisco Pais,

1049 – 001, Lisboa

Portugal

Phone Number (+351) 963359881

E-mail <u>manuel.araujo@ist.utl.pt</u>

# **Current Position**

Since September 2019, I am postdoctoral researcher in the "Higher Structures and Applications" research project (PTDC/MAT-PUR/31089/2017) at the Department of Mathematics of Instituto Superior Técnico. I am interested in Topology in general, particularly Topological Quantum Field Theory and related higher algebraic and categorical structures.

#### **Next Position**

Period | August 2022 - January 2023

Postdoc with the Cambridge Logical Structures Hub, in the Department of Computer Science and Technology at the University of Cambridge.

#### **Previous Positions**

Period | September 2018 – August 2019

Postdoc with the "Mathematics Inspired by String Theory and Quantum Field Theory" group, at the University of Hamburg.

Period | September 2017 – August 2018

Guest at the Max Planck Institute for Mathematics, in Bonn.

Education

Period | September 2013 – August 2017

Degree Obtained | Doctor of Philosophy (D.Phil) in Mathematics (University of Oxford)

Thesis Topic | Coherence for 3-dualizable objects. (supervised by Christopher Douglas)

https://deposit.ora.ox.ac.uk/theses/uuid:a4b8f8de-a8e3-48c3-a742-82316a7bd8eb/file/content01

Period | July 2011 - June 2013

Degree obtained | Master's Degree (MSc) in Mathematics and Applications (IST, Lisbon)

Thesis Topic | Symplectic Embeddings. (supervised by Gustavo Granja)

Period | October 2009 – July 2011

Degree obtained Degree (BSc) in Applied Mathematics and Computation (IST, Lisbon)

Period | September 2007 - July 2009

Degree obtained | Did not finish.

Program | Integrated Master's Degree (MSc) in Electrical and Computer Engineering (IST, Lisbon)

## **Publications**

2017

Symplectic embeddings in infinite codimension. Araújo, M. & Granja, G. J. Homotopy Relat. Struct

(2017). https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40062-017-0189-8
---

	(2017). https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40062-017-0189-8
Preprints	
2022	Coherence for adjunctions in a 4-category. https://arxiv.org/abs/2207.02935
2022	Simple string diagrams and n-sesquicategories. <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2202.09293">https://arxiv.org/abs/2202.09293</a>
2021	Coherence for adjunctions in a 3-category via string diagrams. (accepted for publication in Compositionality) <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2104.09897">https://arxiv.org/abs/2104.09897</a>
2020	String diagrams for 4-categories and fibrations of mapping 4-groupoids. https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.03797
Awards and Scholarships	
2017/2018	Max Planck Institute for Mathematics postdoctoral grant.
2013/2014 - 2015/2016	EPSRC Research Studentship.
2013/2014 - 2015/2016	Christ Church Mathematics Scholarship
2011/2012	FCT Scientific Initiation Grant
2010/2011	IST Merit Scholarship
2010/2011	Gulbenkian Novos Talentos em Matemática Scholarship.
2009/2010	Gulbenkian Novos Talentos em Matemática Scholarship.
2008/2009	FCT Integration Into Research Grant.
2008/2009	IST Merit Diploma.
2007/2008	IST Merit Diploma.
Talks	
March 16, 2022	String diagrams for higher categories. Algebra Seminar, University of Aberdeen.
March 9, 2022	String diagrams for higher categories. TQFT Seminar, Instituto Superior Técnico.
November 2021 – February 2022	Simple string diagrams and n-sesquicategories. Series of 3 talks at Instituto Superior Técnico.
December 17, 2020	Coherence for adjunctions in a 3-category via string diagrams. Informal seminar of the "Higher Structures and Aplications" research group, Instituto Superior Técnico.
September – December 2020	String diagrams for 4-categories and fibrations of mapping 4-groupoids. Series of 4 talks at Instituto Superior Técnico.
November 6, 2019	Coherence for 3-dualizable objects, Mini-meeting on Higher Structures and Applications, Instituto Superior Técnico.
October 23, 2019	Topological Field Theory in dimension 3, TQFT Seminar, Instituto Superior Técnico.
October 23, 2018	Using the cobordism hypothesis to find presentations of bordism categories, Algebra and Mathematical Physics Research Seminar, University of Hamburg

July 10, 2013	rusion categories and 5-dimensional topological field theories, Toding Topologists Meeting, EFFL
June 20, 2013	Symplectic embeddings into CP∞, Seminário Geometria em Lisboa (IST Geometry Seminar).
Research Visits	
April 2016	I spent a month at Stanford University, visiting Christopher Douglas.
May 2015	One month stay at the Trimester program on "Homotopy theory, manifolds, and field theories", Hausdorff Institute for Mathematics, Bonn.
April 2014	One month stay at the MSRI scientific program on Algebraic Topology, Berkeley, California.
Conferences and Summer Schools	
June 2022	Barcelona Conference on Higher Structures, University of Barcelona.
November 2019	Mini-meeting on Higher Structures and Applications, Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisbon.
August 2018	Higher algebra and mathematical physics, Max Planck Institute for Mathematics, Bonn
July 2018	Higher structures in homotopy theory. Isaac Newton Institute, Cambridge.
February 2018	Workshop on Factorisation Algebras and Homology and the Cobordism Hypothesis, Saint-Etienne de Tinée.
July 2016	Young Topologists' Meeting, Copenhagen
June 2016	Topology of manifolds conference, Lisbon
June 2016	European Talbot Workshop on Topological aspects of quantum field theories, Winterberg
July 2015	Young Topologists' Meeting, EPFL
June 2015	Early Career Stage Topologists at Imperial College, Imperial College London
January 2015	"Symmetry and Topology in Quantum Matter" workshop, Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics, UCLA.
October 2014	Masterclass on Topological quantum field theories, quantum groups and 3-manifold invariants (University of Copenhagen).
June 2014	Young Topology Meeting UK, Imperial College London
April 2014	"Reimagining the Foundations of Algebraic Topology" conference, at MSRI.
Teaching Experience	
Trinity 2016 (Apr - Jun)	Tutor for the Part A course "Topology and groups". Exeter College, University of Oxford.
Trinity 2016 (Apr - Jun)	Tutor for the Part A course "Topology". Exeter College, University of Oxford.
Michaelmas 2015 (Oct - Dec)	Tutor for the Part A course "Topology". Exeter College, University of Oxford.
Hilary 2015 (Jan - March)	Tutor for the Part A course "Topology and groups". Exeter College, University of Oxford.
Michaelmas 2014 (Oct - Dec)	Tutor for the Part A course "Topology". Exeter College, University of Oxford.
Hilary 2014 (Jan - March)	Teaching Assistant for the Part C course "Homological Algebra". Mathematical Institute, University of Oxford.
Michaelmas 2013 (Oct - Dec)	Teaching Assistant for the Part C course "Lie Algebras". Mathematical Institute, University of Oxford.

July 10, 2015 Fusion categories and 3-dimensional topological field theories, Young Topologists' Meeting, EPFL